<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Irfan Sharif</title>
    <link>https://irfansharif.github.io/blog/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Irfan Sharif</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://irfansharif.github.io/blog/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Site</title>
      <link>https://irfansharif.github.io/blog/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irfansharif.github.io/blog/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Irfan Sharif, welcome to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://irfansharif.github.io/blog/page/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irfansharif.github.io/blog/page/papers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After each reference, &lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt; links to papers; &lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt; to further information
about that paper, including code and data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;preprints:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;Preprints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutts CS, Eglen SJ (2016) A Bayesian framework for comparing the
structure of spontaneous correlated activity recorded under different
conditions. bioRxiv:037358
&lt;a href=&#34;http://biorxiv.org/content/early/2016/01/19/037358&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ (2015) Bivariate spatial point patterns in the retina: a
reproducible review. bioRxiv:029348
&lt;a href=&#34;http://biorxiv.org/content/early/2015/10/16/029348&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/sje30/eglen2015&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gjorgjieva J, Evers JF, Eglen S (2015) Homeostatic activity-dependent
tuning of recurrent networks for robust propagation of
activity. bioRxiv:033548 &lt;a href=&#34;http://biorxiv.org/content/early/2015/12/02/033548&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2016:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leiwe MN, Hendry AC, Bard AD, Eglen SJ, Lowe AS, Thompson ID (2016)
Geniculo-cortical projection diversity revealed within the mouse
visual thalamus. PLoS One
11:e0144846. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0144846&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlesworth P, Morton A, Eglen SJ, Komiyama NH, Grant SGN (2016)
Canalization of genetic and pharmacological perturbations in
developing primary neuronal activity patterns. Neuropharmacology
100:47–55. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropharm.2015.07.027&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://damtp.cam.ac.uk/user/sje30/papers/charlesworth2015_data.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2015:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hjorth JJJ, Savier E, Sterratt DC, Reber M, Eglen SJ (2015b)
Estimating the location and size of retinal injections from orthogonal
images of an intact retina. BMC Neurosci 16:80.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/s12868-015-0217-8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Hjorthmedh/IntactEye&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budd JML, Cuntz H, Eglen SJ, Krieger P (2015) Editorial: Quantitative
Analysis of Neuroanatomy. Front Neuroanat 9:143.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2015.00143&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hjorth JJJ, Sterratt DC, Cutts CS, Willshaw DJ, Eglen SJ (2015a)
Quantitative assessment of computational models for retinotopic map
formation. Dev Neurobiol 75:641–666.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22241&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Hjorthmedh/RetinalMap&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlesworth P, Cotterill E, Morton A, Grant SGN, Eglen SJ (2015)
Quantitative differences in developmental profiles of spontaneous
activity in cortical and hippocampal cultures. Neural Dev 10:1.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neuraldevelopment.com/content/10/1/1/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sje30/g2chvc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2014:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutts CS, Eglen SJ (2014) Detecting Pairwise Correlations in Spike
Trains: An Objective Comparison of Methods and Application to the
Study of Retinal Waves. JNeuroscience 34:14288–14303.
[&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;]()
[&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen S (2014a) Open access: sharing your data is easier than you think. Nature 510:340.
[&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;]()
[&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maccione A, Hennig MH, Gandolfo M, Muthmann O, van Coppenhagen J, Eglen SJ, Berdondini L, Sernagor E (2014) Following the ontogeny of retinal waves: pan-retinal recordings of population dynamics in the neonatal mouse. J Physiol 592:1545–1563.
[&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;]()
[&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ (2014b) Retinotopic Development, Models of. In: Encyclopedia of Computational Neuroscience, pp 1–4. Springer New York.
[&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;]()
[&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schottdorf M, Eglen SJ, Wolf F, Keil W (2014) Can retinal ganglion cell dipoles seed iso-orientation domains in the visual cortex? PLoS One 9:e86139.
[&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;]()
[&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Weeks M, Jessop M, Simonotto J, Jackson T, Sernagor E (2014)
A data repository and analysis framework for spontaneous neural
activity recordings in developing retina. Gigascience 3:3.
[&lt;em&gt;Paper&lt;/em&gt;]()
[&lt;em&gt;Info&lt;/em&gt;]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2013:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gjorgjieva J, Berni J, Evers JF, Eglen SJ (2013) Neural circuits for
peristaltic wave propagation in crawling Drosophila larvae: analysis
and modeling. Front Comput Neurosci 7:24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2012:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hore VRA, Troy JB, Eglen SJ (2012) Parasol cell mosaics are unlikely
to drive the formation of structured orientation maps in primary
visual cortex. Vis Neurosci 29:283–299.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeley PW, Sliff BJ, Lee SCS, Fuerst PG, Burgess RW, Eglen SJ, Reese
BE (2012) Neuronal clustering and fasciculation phenotype in Dscam-
and Bax-deficient mouse retinas. J Comp Neurol 520:1349–1364.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chabrol FP, Eglen SJ, Sernagor E (2012) GABAergic control of retinal
ganglion cell dendritic development. Neuroscience 227:30–43.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2011:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gjorgjieva J, Eglen SJ (2011) Modeling developmental patterns of
spontaneous activity. Curr Opin Neurobiol 21:679–684.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2009:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gjorgjieva J, Toyoizumi T, Eglen SJ (2009) Burst-time-dependent plasticity robustly guides ON/OFF segregation in the lateral geniculate nucleus. PLoS Comput Biol 5:e1000618.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Godfrey KB, Eglen SJ, Swindale NV (2009) A multi-component model of the developing retinocollicular pathway incorporating axonal and synaptic growth. PLoS Comput Biol 5:e1000600.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ (2009) A Quick Guide to Teaching R Programming to Computational Biology Students. PLoS Comput Biol 5:e1000482.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2008:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Lofgreen DD, Raven MA, Reese BE (2008) Analysis of spatial relationships in three dimensions: tools for the study of nerve cell patterning. BMC Neurosci 9:68.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Wong JCT (2008) Spatial constraints underlying the retinal mosaics of two types of horizontal cells in cat and macaque. Vis Neurosci 25:209–214.
p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2007:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2006:3040ef68935035b2c4d6e100309f4ec9&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ (2006) Development of regular cellular spacing in the retina: theoretical models. Math Med Biol 23:79–99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sernagor E, Eglen SJ, Harris WA, Wong ROL eds. (2006) Retinal Development. Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Diggle PJ, Troy JB (2005) Homotypic constraints dominate positioning of on- and off-center beta retinal ganglion cells. Vis Neurosci 22:859–871.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kishi M, Kummer TT, Eglen SJ, Sanes JR (2005) LL5beta: a regulator of postsynaptic differentiation identified in a screen for synaptically enriched transcripts at the neuromuscular junction. J Cell Biol 169:355–366.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Raven MA, Tamrazian E, Reese BE (2003b) Dopaminergic amacrine cells in the inner nuclear layer and ganglion cell layer comprise a single functional retinal mosaic. J Comp Neurol 466:343–355.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sernagor E, Young C, Eglen SJ (2003) Developmental Modulation of Retinal Wave Dynamics: Shedding Light on the GABA Saga. JNeuroscience 23:7621–7629.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raven MA, Eglen SJ, Ohab JJ, Reese BE (2003) Determinants of the exclusion zone in dopaminergic amacrine cell mosaics. J Comp Neurol 461:123–136.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Galli-Resta L, Reese BE (2003a) Theoretical models of retinal mosaic formation. In: Modeling neural development (van Ooyen A, ed), pp 133–150. MIT Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lee CW, Eglen SJ, Wong ROL (2002) Segregation of on and off Retinogeniculate Connectivity Directed by Patterned Spontaneous Activity. J Neurophysiol 88:2311–2321.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, van Ooyen A, Willshaw DJ (2000) Lateral cell movement driven by dendritic interactions is sufficient to form retinal mosaics. Network 11:103–118.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sernagor E, Eglen SJ, O’Donovan MJ (2000) Differential Effects of Acetylcholine and Glutamate Blockade on the Spatiotemporal Dynamics of Retinal Waves. JNeuroscience 20:RC56.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ, Willshaw DJ (2000) Estimating the influence of cell fate, mediated by lateral inhibition, upon the development of retinal mosaics. EurJNeuroscience 12 (Supplement 11):486.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ (2000) An evaluation of competitive and cell death mechanisms in forming on- and off-centre retinal ganglion cell mosaics. In: Ninth Annual Computational Neuroscience Meeting, CNS-2000, pp 45.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eglen SJ (1999) The role of retinal waves and synaptic normalization in retinogeniculate development. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 354:497–506.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bowns L, Eglen SJ (1994) Extraction of non-fourier orientation information for texture classification. Investigative Opthalmology and Visual Science 35:1406.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>