<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on irfansharif.io</title>
    <link>https://irfansharif.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on irfansharif.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://irfansharif.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Without Atomic Clocks</title>
      <link>https://irfansharif.io/blog/living-without-atomic-clocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irfansharif.io/blog/living-without-atomic-clocks/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8853; The world&#39;s first caesium-133 atomic clock (1955), and mostly unrelated everything else here.  This was originally authored by Spencer about four years ago, and we figured it could do with a refresh. You&amp;rsquo;ll also find it on our company engineering blog.
One of the more inspired facets of Spanner comes from its use of atomic clocks to give participating nodes really accurate wall time synchronization. The designers of Spanner call this &amp;lsquo;TrueTime&amp;rsquo;, and it provides a tight bound on clock offset between any two nodes in the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template</title>
      <link>https://irfansharif.io/blog/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://irfansharif.io/blog/template/</guid>
      <description>Donec vehicula massa mi Nunc tempus, mauris quis convallis vestibulum, dui quam cursus nulla, ut ornare arcu erat vitae mi. Quisque varius porttitor mattis. Donec ornare convallis enim facilisis dignissim. Morbi sit amet tristique odio. Nulla luctus bibendum justo. Nam orci mauris, dapibus at ultricies at, rhoncus vel dolor. Donec at lectus at velit pulvinar bibendum vel nec arcu. Ut viverra luctus velit nec tincidunt. Donec hendrerit, nulla sit amet rhoncus rutrum, orci est sodales ligula, quis malesuada lacus felis non leo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>